字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
领衔主演
西尔维娅·克里斯蒂
导演
贾斯特·杰克金
查泰菜夫人的情人
主演
尼古拉斯·克莱
谢恩·布赖恩特
安·米切尔
伊丽莎白·斯普里格斯
快点，安东，我要和你比赛，跑啊！
Come on, Anton, I'll race you. Get up!
- 看，他们来了  - 咱们去告诉大家
- Look, they're coming.  - Let's go and tell everyone.
- 康妮，我赢了  - 我就知道你会赢
- Connie, I won.  - I knew you would.
- 你永远赢不了我  - 这次赌什么？
- you'll never beat me, as usual.  - What was the bet this time?
和新婚的查泰菜夫人跳第一个舞的荣幸
The honour of having the first dance with the new Lady Chatterley.
这位夫人很漂亮
This one's pretty enough...
可我听说她是艺术家的女儿
...but I understand she's the daughter of an artist.
她正是克利福德和这所老宅子所需要的
She's just what Clifford and this old house needs.
她有着别人永远无法拥有的活力
She's alive in the way the others never could be.
- 需求面前无法律，我的朋友  - 政治，都是政治
- Necessity knows no law, my friends.  - Politics, politics.
- 要想毁掉聚会，就请德国人来  - 安东，咱们现在还不是敌人呢
- How to ruin a party: Invite a German.  - Anton, we're not enemies yet.
- 可是形势很严峻  - 拜托，今晚别说这事
- But the situation is serious.  - Please, not this evening.
- 为什么不和我妻子跳个舞？ - 荣幸至致，失陪一下
- Why don't you dance with my wife?  - With pleasure. Excuse me.
女士们，先生们，请大家注意啦
Ladies and gentlemen, may I have your attention, please?
非常抱歉打断大家跳舞，但我保证你们很愿意听到这个消息
I'm sorry to interrupt the dance, but I'm sure you'll want to hear the news.
在刚才的二十四分钟里，英国和德国已经处于交战状态
For the last 24 minutes, England has been at war with Germany.
让我们国干杯
Let us drink to England.
英国
England.
- 英国  - 英国
- England.  - England.
- 当然也为德国  - 为德国
- And to Germany, of course.  - To Germany.
- 也为英国  - 为德国
- And to England.  - Germany.
再见，姨妈，请照顾好康妮
Goodbye, Auntie. Look after Connie.
- 我很快就会回来  - 再见，希尔达
- I can't be long.  - Goodbye, Hilda.
再见，再见啦
Goodbye. Goodbye.
- 亲爱的，我不希望你去送我  - 真的吗？
- Darling, I'd rather you didn't come.  - Are you sure?
- 克里夫，多多保重  - 罗伯兹
- Cliff, take care of yourself.  - Roberts.
我应该能回来赶上猎野鸡的季节
Should be back just in time for the pheasant season.
冲啊，弟兄们！
Come on, Iads!
冲啊！向前冲！
Go on! Forwards!
快点！冲啊，快！
Faster! Go on, faster!
保持队形！保持队形！
Keep the line! Keep the line!
冲啊！向前冲！冲啊！
Forwards! Forwards, forwards!
上，弟兄们！
Go on, Iads!
冲啊！
Forwards!
哥们，这人还有口气
This one's still breathing, Paddy.
“你可以坐下，沃辛先生” 她在口袋里找着铅笔
"you can take a seat, Mr. Worthing." She looks in her pocket for a pencil.
“谢谢，布莱克奈夫人，我喜欢站着”
"Thank you, Lady Bracknell, I prefer standing."
布菜克奈夫人手里拿着笔记本说
Lady Bracknell, notebook in hand:
“我这份合格者名单上没有你
"you are not down on my list of eligible young men...
这和波尔顿女公爵的名单是一样的，我们一起做的
...but it's the same list the Duchess of Bolton has. We work together.
不过，如果你能回答一位慈爱母亲的问题
However, I will enter your name should your answers be...
我就可以把你的名字加上”
...what an affectionate mother requires.
“你抽烟吗？”“抽，必须承认，我抽烟”
Do you smoke?" "yes, I must admit, I smoke."
“很高兴听你这样说”
"I am glad to hear it."
十点半了，该睡觉了，亲爱的
10:30. It's time to go to bed, darling.
又是一天过去了
Dear, dear, another day gone.
谢谢，亲爱的，我自己来
Thank you, darling, I can manage.
晚安，康妮
Good night, Connie.
早上好
Good morning.
斯图尔特勋爵夫妇那美丽的家，弗里奇利大厦公开出售了
Fritchley Hall, the home of Lord and Lady Stewart is offered for sale.
有传言说，马特洛克附近的西普利家可能会遭到同样命运
It's rumoured that Shipley, near Matlock, may suffer the same fate.
好像整个世界都在我们周围崩溃
It's as if the whole world is collapsing around us.
怎么回事，亲爱的？
What's that, darling?
他们要卖掉弗里奇利大厦和西普利家的房子
They want to sell Fritchley Hall and Shipley.
我看这样的事会一件接一件发生
I suppose the one thing pushes out the other.
咱们怎么样？咱们这房子呢？
But what about us? Here? This house?
除了变化本身，什么都在变
Everything changes except change itself.
我想我要抽根雪茄
I fancy a cigar is called for.
我自己来，谢谢你，菲尔德．
I can manage. Thank you, Field.
- 今天晚上就到这了  - 好的，先生
- That will be all for this evening.  - Very good, sir.
我觉得你很了不起，真的
I think you're wonderful, I do, really.
- 为什么？ - 你能这样陪着克利夫德
- Why?  - The way you are with Clifford.
我觉得这太了不起了，可怜的孩子…
I think it's wonderful, really. Poor boy...
伤残成这样了
...so crippled as he is.
最多只能算半个男人，可以这么说
Not more than half a man, you might say.
对我这样的女人来说没什么
It's the right half for a woman like me.
他说话妙语连珠，机智诙谐
He can be so witty and entertaining.
不过对一位年轻的妻子那就不好说了
But for a young wife, I'm not so sure at all.
- 要不要来一根？ - 谢谢，我自己有
- Care for one of mine?  - Thank you, I have one of my own.
我嫁给理查德时非常年轻
I was very young when I married Richard.
我们想搞改革、搞政治，诸如此类，什么都想
We wanted reform, politics, all that sort of thing.
我们也那样做了，可从他去世后，尽管有孩子们
And we got it. But ever since he died, despite the children...
我还是觉得活着毫无意义，这种感觉太可怕了
...I feel I've lived for nothing. It's a dreadful feeling.
知道自己来到世上要做的事，死的时候肯定完不成
To know you're bound to die without having the things you were born for.
死？谁要死？
Die? Who's going to die?
我死过又活了，所以我要说永生
I've been there and back. Immortality.
我们来到世上为了什么？我觉得人生在世好像有很多事
What are we born for? It seems to me that we are born for so many things.
又好像什么都没有
Or perhaps we're not born for anything at all.
这只是我们下决心的问题
It's just a matter of making up our minds.
- 为永生干杯  - 为永生
- Immortality.  - Immortality.
我觉得女人应该经历更多的事
I think women should experiment more.
得到你年轻时想要的一切
Get what you want in your youth.
如果一个女人随着年华逝去，觉得自己虚度了光阴
Nothing is so bad for a woman getting on in years...
还有什么比这更糟的
...than the thought that she's missed.
晚安，亲爱的
Good night, dear.
我明天一大早离开，所以见不到你了
I'm leaving early in the morning, so I can't see you again.
没有什么能比一个被徒劳无益的悔恨
There's nothing so sad or futile...
纠缠着的老妇人更悲哀更无助的了
...as an elderly woman possessed by vain regrets.
我要疯了
I am possessed.
康妮，我得跟你谈谈
Connie, I need to talk to you.
坐一会儿吧
Sit down a moment.
从某种意义上说，你是最悲惨的失败者
you know, you're the worst loser, in a sense.
- 亲爱的  - 我依赖你，靠你而活
- Darling.  - I depend on you, live on you.
而你放弃了生命中极为重要的部分
But you're denied a serious part of life.
你放弃的东西尝在你的潜意识中起作用，伤害你
The fact you are denied, it may work inside your subconscious, harming you.
可你知道我需要你就像你需要我一样
But you know I need you as much as you need me.
- 以前你很需要我，对吗？ - 当然了
- you did want me before, didn't you?  - Of course.
我知道，所以这才让人心酸
I know, and it's bitter.
我不想让你觉得你在为我牺牲
you see, I don't want you to feel you've brought me a sacrifice.
康妮，我必须跟你说，如果有个男人
Connie, I must tell you this. If ever there's a man...
你非常想让他和你做爱
...who you absolutely want to make love to you...
那就接受他吧，如果你想，就找个情人吧
...take him. Have a lover if you want to.
快看，老鹰
Look, a kestrel.
永远不要忘记，我爱你
Don't ever forget I love you.
- 嗨，过来  - 过来，宝贝
- Hey, come on here.  - Come here, girl.
过来，快过来
Come on up. Come on up.
- 对不起，这狗打扰你们了  - 别担心，它是个好狗
- I'm sorry about the dog, sir.  - Don't worry, she's a good girl.
你能不能把我推回房子？
Look, will you give me a push back to the house?
- 你好，夫人  - 你好
- Milady.  - Hello.
好了，拉吧
All right, pull.
谢谢，迈勒斯
Thank you, Mellors.
谢谢，菲尔德
Thank you, Field.
克利夫德？
Clifford?
要帮忙吗？
Do you need some help?
- 不用，马上就好了  - 咱们去年情况怎么样？
- No, nearly done now.  - How did we do last year?
还可以，连鸡都卖得不错
Not bad, considering. Even the pheasants sold quite well.
那煤矿呢？是不是应该重新开张？
What about the mine? Shouldn't you open it again?
- 我听说现在煤…  - 还不是时候
- I heard that coal...  - Not the right time.
现在时机不好
Not the right time at all.
康妮
Connie.
没事，亲爱的，别着急
It's all right, darling. Don't worry.
我烦透了这些唱片，亲爱的
I'm sick and tired of these records, darling.
- 能不能像往常那样为我弹点什么？ - 你想要我弹什么？
- Could you play me something?  - What would you like me to play?
喜欢什么弹什么，你知道有首曲子你弹得特别好
Whatever you like. you know the one. The one you play so well.
那好吧
All right, then.
克利夫德！
Clifford!
快去叫克里斯蒂医生
Call for Dr. Christie.
医生马上就来了
The doctor's on his way.
他们来了，夫人
They're here, milady.
不过不是医生，是护士
But it's not the doctor, it's a nurse.
我是伯尔顿太太，听到消息马上就赶了过来
I'm Mrs. Bolton. I came as quickly as I could.
- 你的气色也不好  - 不，我没事
- you look ill too.  - No, I'm fine.
一点都不好，我先给他看，然后再给你看
Far from fine. I'll take a look at him first, then I'll take a look at you.
没事，我没事
I'm fine. I'm fine.
下午好，克利夫德先生
Good afternoon, Sir Clifford.
伯尔顿太太，我什么事都没有
I'm perfectly all right.
如果不介意，让我看看再说吧，感觉怎么不好？
I'll decide, if you don't mind. What seems to be the trouble?
没什么新鲜的，还是老毛病
Nothing new, just the same old nonsense.
这回是肩膀，还是可恶的脊椎引起的
It's my shoulders this time, and what's left of my damned spine.
- 这天气真是拜上帝所赐  - 只要不发大水就好
- This weather is a godsend.  - Providing we don't get a flood.
不会的，不出这星期就会放晴
We won't. It'll clear up.
有什么我可以做的？
Isn't there anything I can do?
- 告诉我，如果再犯了我该怎么办？  - 好的
- Show me, in case it happens again.  - We'll see.
有你可做的事，去看看迈勒斯有没有让鸡孵蛋
you can do something. See if Mellors is setting eggs under the birds.
我们去年就孵了，希望今年做得更好
We did well last year. I want to do even better.
克利夫德，那事现在并不重要
Clifford, that's not important now.
新鲜空气和健康的运动
Fresh air and healthy activity...
是我给你开的药方，夫人
...that's my prescription for you, milady.
疼痛没什么可怕的
Pain is nothing to fear.
那是身体在告诉我们什么地方出了毛病
It's just the body's way of telling us that something's amiss.
好了，转过来吧
Right, on your back.
康妮，这么快就回来了？迈勒斯怎么说？
Connie, you're back early. What did Mellors say?
我没找到他
I couldn't find him.
康妮，这么简单的事都不能让你做
Connie, I can't ask you to do the simplest thing.
给你的，夫人
That's for you, milady.
- 这是什么？ - 奎宁和一些草药
- What is it?  - Just some quinine and herbs.
希望不是春药
Hope it's not a love potion.
伯尔顿太太要在这儿过夜，请把蓝色房间给她收拾一下
Mrs. Bolton is spending the night. Organise the blue room for her.
- 好的  - 喝了吧．
- Of course.  - Drink up.
你今天够累的，克利夫德先生，必须好好休息
you've had a tiring day, Sir Clifford. you must get some rest.
- 伯尔顿太太，我来照顾我丈夫吧  - 好的，夫人
- I'll look after my husband.  - Certainly, milady.
- 晚安，克利夫德先生，晚安，夫人  - 晚安，谢谢你
- Good night, Sir Clifford and milady.  - Good night, and thank you.
- 什么这么好笑？ - 《哈吉巴巴历险记》
- Now, what's so funny?  - The Adventures of Hajji Baba.
他厌恶不蒙面莎的英国女人
He's repelled by the naked faces of English women.
如果她们蒙上脸
If only they'd covered their faces...
那他身上将燃起怎样的激情
...what fire of passion would have run through him.
这太有趣了
That's amusing.
人们除了脸别的地方都看不见，也许是一种遗憾
It's a pity we never see anything of people but their face.
毕竟对于大多数人来说，脸是最难看的
After all, the worst part of most people is their face.
你是说我们应该蒙着脸光着身子外出？
you mean if we covered our faces and walked about naked?
像雷诺阿那样，可以呀
Like Renoir. Why not?
没有头的躯干部雕像往往非常漂亮
And a torso in sculpture is often so lovely without a head.
- 它有着自己的生命  - 也许吧
- It has a life of its own.  - Perhaps.
对不起，如果我今天下午让你扫兴
Sorry if I was unpleasant this afternoon.
早上好，夫人
Good morning, milady.
象应该这样走，对吧？
And the bishop moves this way, yes?
- 对，马应该…  - 斜两格前进一格
- That's right, and the knight moves...  - One ahead and two diagonally.
你真漂亮，今天想干什么？
you look beautiful. What are you gonna do today?
没什么特别的
Nothing in particular.
如果没什么更好的事，为什么不再去一趟？
If you've nothing better to do, why not try again?
- 千什么？ - 看看鸡孵蛋没有
- Try what?  - Find out about the pheasant's eggs.
- 你要我去，我就去吧  - 谢谢，亲爱的
- If you want me to.  - Thank you, darling.
走这儿
There.
- 你可真快  - 是的，先生
- you're very quick.  - That I am, sir.
对不起，夫人
Excuse me, ma'am.
别叫，嗨
Quiet. Hey.
趴下
Lie down.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello.  - Hello.
- 有什么事吗？ - 先生想知道你什么时候让鸡孵蛋？
- What can I do for you?  - When will you set the eggs?
已经孵上了，都安排好了，告诉他，情况比去年好
Already started. It's under control. Be better than last year, tell him.
- 可以吗？ - 当然可以
- May I?  - If you'd like.
- 这里很让人感觉很愉快  - 是吗？
- It's very pleasant here.  - you think so?
是的，我会来看看那些鸡，看它们一天天长大
yes. I shall come here and see the birds, watch them grow.
是吗？
Will you, now?
那小屋有两把钥匙吧？
Are there two keys to the hut?
- 听见我说话了吗？ - 只有一把
- Do you hear me?  - There's only one key.
- 你能不能再配一把？ - 可以倒是可以
- Couldn't you have one made?  - Aye, we could.
为什么克利夫德先生不给你建个凉亭？
Only, why doesn't Sir Clifford build a little summerhouse for you?
不用，我就是想看鸡孵蛋
No, I want to watch the pheasants.
这里只能有我一个人，那些鸡在孵蛋呢
I have to be on me own, now that the birds are laying.
- 我不会打扰它们  - 鸡不喜欢周围有陌生人
- I can't interfere.  - Birds don't like strangers around.
- 我要一把钥匙，什么时候给我？ - 我到底要听几个人的？
- I want a key. When can I have it?  - How many bosses do I have, anyway?
那你就别配钥匙，再说了，我根本就不想再来这里
Don't make a key. On second thought, I don't ever want to be here again.
克利夫德？把你的话传达给迈勒斯了，这是什么？
Clifford? I gave Mellors your message. What's this?
我决定再磨炼一下自己的手，想起雷诺阿了
I've decided to try my hand again, thinking of Renoir.
- 真是个好主意  - 没错，我以前一直画得不太好
- What a good idea.  - Of course, I was never very good.
不知道会画成什么样，反正已经开始了
I wonder what I'll see now, after all that's happened.
- 给我画幅像吧  - 那你得排队等着
- Well, there's always me.  - you'll have to join the queue.
- 伯尔顿太太已经提出了要求  - 怎么可能？
- Mrs. B's already asked.  - How can she?
- 她要住上一段时间  - 没什么严重的事吧？
- She's gonna stay a while.  - Nothing serious, is it?
没有，她只是想让你更自由一些
No, she just thought it would free you more.
她要给我做康复，所以要住下
She'll give me my exercises. She may as well be here.
- 这样不是很好吗？ - 是很好
- It's marvellous, isn't it?  - Marvellous.
伯尔顿太太，你要和我们住上一阵，这太好了
you'll be staying with us a while. That's good.
我觉得这样最好，你今天找到迈勒斯先生了吗？
I think it's for the best. Did you find Mr. Mellors today?
找到了，他是我见过的最没礼貌的人
I did. He's the most insolent man I've ever talked to.
他从小就是个目中无人的小坏蛋
He was a defiant little demon, even when he was a lad.
- 你认识他？ - 大家都认识他，他就喜欢独来独往
- you know him, then?  - He prefers to keep his own company.
我觉得只要有人能接近他，他还是很有感情的
I thought he had a heart, if anybody could get there.
- 有感情？ - 他让许多女人觉得难以接近
- A heart.  - He just gets most women's backs up.
就像他对你那样
Like he has with you.
- 梅花  - 我出A
- Club.  - Ace.
你不能那样，你作弊，拿回去
you can't do that. you're cheating.
那是你的，该我了，我出J
That's you. My go. Jack.
- 换牌  - 我累了，我想上楼了
- Card change.  - I'm tired. I think I'll go up.
- 晚安，伯尔顿太太  - 晚安，去人
- Good night.  - Good night.
- 晚安，亲爱的  - 晚安
- Good night, darling.  - Good night.
- 我出十  - 十
- Ten.  - Ten.
- 八，换牌  - 换同花？
- Eight and change.  - Change of suit?
- 是的  - 要哪个花色？
- yes.  - To what?
- 梅花  - 给你梅花
- Clubs.  - Clubs.
克利夫德，我有个问题，你说了我应该找个情人
Clifford, I have a problem. you said I should take a lover.
- 想让我帮你挑吗？ - 不是，如果有了孩子怎么办？
- Want me to choose for you, do you?  - No, but what if I have a child?
如果我有孩子，你会介意吗？
Would you mind if I had a child?
- 有谁的孩子？ - 不知道，你会介意吗？
- If you had whose child?  - I don't know.
你能不能保证那是圣灵的雾
Couldn't you promise it'd be by the Holy Ghost?
- 你会介意吗？ - 谁的孩子？
- Would you mind?  - Whose child?
但是你会问？
But need you ask?
是不是别人会那样看，孩子是圣灵的？
Isn't it the Holy Ghost if one looks at it that way?
好吧，亲爱的，生育是自然法则
All right, my dear, breed. It's nature's law.
我相信我的儿子，他的父亲配得上准男爵
I trust my son and heir will have a father worthy of a baronet.
当然，我相信你的品味
But I trust your taste.
- 这对你们俩都是一种牺牲  - 为什么而牺牲？
- It is a sacrifice for both of you.  - A sacrifice to what?
上帝的意愿
To God's will.
你能不能脱开虔诚的外表
Can't you come out from under your pieties...
像男人对女人那样和我说话？
...and speak to me as a man to a woman?
- 想要我宽恕你做的什么事吗？ - 不是
- To condone something you have done?  - No.
如果你把事情看作是一段时间的尝试
Perhaps if you look upon things as a period of trial...
也许就能找到答案了
...in time, you will find your way.
- 再见，神父  - 再见
- Good afternoon, Father.  - Good afternoon.
一段时间的尝试
A period of trial.
别动，伯尔顿太太
Keep still, Mrs. B.
你坐了那么长时间都不烦，真是很难得
This is hard enough without you fidgeting all the time.
- 哦，是你呀  - 打得不错
- Oh, it's you.  - Not bad.
- 想认真打一盘吗？  - 如果你愿意当然可以，很可能你赢
- Want to play seriously?  - If you like. you'll probably win.
我对这种打法还没太掌握
I haven't got the hang of it this way.
我要是能赢，那就是风向变了
Well, it'll be a change for me to win.
听说你今天做了件和你性格不太相符的事
I hear you did something rather out of character today.
- 去教堂了，是吗？ - 是的
- Went to church, did you?  - yes.
为什么要去？
What on earth for?
我想去和圣灵预约一下
I thought I'd book an appointment with the Holy Ghost.
夫人
Milady.
坐一
Sit.
- 有事吗，迈勒斯？ - 你的钥匙配好了，夫人
- yes, Mellors?  - Got that key for you, milady.
- 很麻烦吗？ - 不，怎么会呢，不麻烦
- Was it a lot of trouble?  - No. How could it be?
- 那就谢谢你了  - 走吧
- Thank you, then.  - Come on.
- 早上好，亲爱的  - 早上好
- Good morning.  - Morning.
- 早上好  - 早上好，我来晚了吗？
- Morning.  - Morning. am I late?
- 没有，一点都不晚  - 睡得好吗，夫人？
- Not at all.  - Did you sleep well, milady?
谢谢，伯尔顿太太，我去吃早餐了
Thank you, Mrs. Bolton. Well, I'll have some breakfast.
好的，一会儿见
yes, see you later.
进去吧
Go in there.
来吧，小东西，过来吧
Come on, my little ones, come on.
过来吧，小家伙们，过来
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello.  - Hello.
真为克利夫德先生感到惋惜
Shame about Sir Clifford, isn't it?
有年轻漂亮的妻子和这片土地，却没有孩子跑来跑去
Fair, young wife and this land and no children to pass it on to.
这说明你太不了解他了，克利夫德先生身体一直在不断好转
That shows how little you know. Sir Clifford's getting stronger.
谢谢，罗伯特，就停在这儿吧
Thank you, Robert. That will be all.
我开的药方好像起作用了
My prescription seems to have worked.
- 你为克利夫德做得很好  - 我是说新鲜空气和健康的运动
- you've done wonders for Clifford.  - I meant fresh air, healthy activity.
对女人来说，如果心死了，生命也就没多少意必了
It's not much of a life for a woman if her heart never works.
有很多人其实并没有心
There's many who have no real hearts.
如果有心的话，你就不会为了钱而活着
But if you've got a heart, you don't want to live for money.
你说得很对
I'm sure you're right.
如果一个人的话超过了她应该说的，那就是因为
If there's something to make one say more than one should, it's because...
你是个真正的女人，她的心在为你燃烧，而不是反对你
...you're a true woman and a body's heart burns for you, not against you.
我知道你不会做反对我的事
I know you wouldn't do anything against me.
任何人都不会反对，如果我能帮上忙的话
Neither shall anyone else if I can help it.
好孩子
Good girl.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello.  - Hello.
你没生病呀
you weren't ill then.
护士走了，所以我要陪克利夫德先生
Nurse went away, so I stayed with Sir Clifford.
哦，这样啊
I see.
- 多么可爱，多么柔软啊  - 是啊，可爱的小东西
- What lovely, soft creatures.  - Aye, pretty young things.
- 给你  - 过来，宝贝
- There.  - Come, baby.
- 它们不喜欢我  - 那就找个喜欢的
- They don't like me.  - Then we'll find one that does.
来
Go on.
这不值得哭
It's not worth crying for.
好啦，好啦
There, there.
没事啦
It's all right.
你真漂亮
you're beautiful.
太美了
So beautiful.
对不起，来晚了，为什么今天不让我来做呢？你可以走了
I'm sorry I'm late. Why don't I do that today? you're excused.
- 很好，夫人  - 这主意好
- Very good, milady.  - What a nice idea.
想赛一盘吗？
Want a game in a minute?
我不想再赢你了
I don't want to beat you again.
今天你赢不了，我一直在练习
you won't today. I've been practising.
- 别走，伯尔顿太太  - 有事吗，夫人？
- Don't go, Mrs. Bolton.  - Excuse me, milady.
- 一起喝茶吧，你也是家里的一员  - 谢谢
- Join us, you're part of the family.  - Thank you.
- 你喜欢什么样的茶？ - 很浓，加好多糖
- How do you like your tea?  - Very strong, lots of sugar.
又浓又甜的茶
Strong, sweet tea.
我的口味是从我丈夫那儿来的
I got the taste from my husband.
- 他去世很多年了吗？ - 我当时二十四岁
- Is it many years since he died?  - I was 24.
- 太可怕了  - 是啊，和你守寡的年纪一样，康妮
- How awful.  - yes, same age you were widowed, Con.
我们正努力帮你站起来，不是吗？
Now, we're going to get you back on your feet, aren't we?
- 是的  - 不知道你是怎么熬过来的
- yes.  - I don't know how you lived through it.
我自己也没想到
I didn't think I could.
心起了很太作用，我怀念他，从来没有忘记他
The heart makes up for a lot. I miss him, but I'll never forget him.
他从来没有离开我，我也决不会离开他
He'd never have left me, and I'll never leave him.
这是给我们大家上的一课，康妮
A lesson to us all, Con.
我是说，这非常感人，伯尔顿太太
I mean, that's very touching, Mrs. B.
- 你永远不会离开我，对吧，康妮？ - 克利夫德
- you'll never leave me, will you?  - Clifford.
一旦你在心里认为自己是妻子，那就永远是妻子
Once a wife in your heart, always a wife, I say.
走啊，伯尔顿太太
Come on, Mrs. B.
- 我的脑子都不转了  - 不想赢光我所有的钱啦？
- Can't think straight.  - Don't you want to win all my money?
- 天太晚了  - 别埋怨
- It's late.  - Don't complain.
将军
Check.
太好了
Very good.
天快亮了，你想睡的话，就去睡吧
It must be early light now. you can go to bed if you like.
走之前把窗帘拉开，好吗？
Open the curtains before you leave, would you?
- 你们把这些东西拿到哪儿去？ - 克利夫德先生吩咐
- Where are you taking this?  - Sir Clifford's instructions.
- “把它们埋藏到阁楼上”  - 他在哪儿呢？
- " Bury it in the attic," he said.  - Where is he?
- 和两位先生在书房里  - 谢谢，菲尔德
- With two gentlemen in the library.  - Thank you, Field.
我认为现在正是时机，但我们必须把设备现代化
Now is the right time, but we simply must have the bits modernised.
特别是橡树林矿，因为我们可以最大限度地开采…
Especially the Oakwood Pit. We can exploit that to the last possibility...
- 早上好  - 各位，这是我妻子
- Good morning, everybody.  - Gentlemen, my wife.
你好
How do you do?
亲爱的，能不能让我们安安静静说会话？拜托！
Darling, would you let us talk in peace? Please!
刚才说到哪儿了？
Now, where were we?
坐下吧
Sit down.
- 我做错什么了吗？ - 没有
- Have I done something wrong?  - No.
你觉得和我在一起贬低自己了吗？
you think you've lowered yourself with me?
没有
No.
使劲！好，另一侧
Push! Good. And the other side.
使劲，使劲
And push, push.
你必须让肩膀使劲，休息一下
you must strengthen these shoulders. And rest.
- 你真的觉得有希望吗？ - 你相信我吗？
- Do you really think there's hope?  - Do you trust me?
- 相信，伯尔顿太太  - 那好，咱们再来
- yes, Mrs. B.  - Well, then, try again.
向上抬，使劲
Lift and push.
好，就这样，好
Good, good, good.
休息一下，好
And rest. Good.
我觉得你好可爱
you're lovely to me.
- 摸起来好舒服  - 不要哭
- So lovely to touch.  - Don't cry.
我曾读过这样一段话
I read something one day:
“我要经历人生中的一切
" I will experience everything in life...
这样，当我走上通往死亡的最后旅程
...so on the final journey to my death...
我的夜晚就不会被懊悔吞噬”
...the nights will not be haunted by regret."
所以用不着哭
So no need to cry.
别担心，这真的很幸福
Don't worry, it's really happiness.
人都去哪儿了？
Where are the others?
克利夫德先生在书房，不让别人打扰他
Sir Clifford is in the library and asked not to be disturbed.
伯尔顿太太在午睡
Mrs. Bolton is taking a nap.
- 那这是专门为我准备的了  - 是的，夫人
- Well, it will be just for me, then.  - yes, milady.
这份杂志是你的
This magazine came for you.
康妮
Connie.
我亲爱的的康妮，你很开心吧？
My darling Connie. Are you happy?
- 怎么了？ - 因为你的样子非常可爱
- Why?  - Because you look so adorable.
如果你不开心，我会受不了的
I couldn't bear it if you were unhappy.
你太好心了
So kind.
我真心认为我应该死去，他们应该让我死
I honestly think I should have died. They should have let me.
克利夫德，别这样，如果某种东西失去了，那并不意味着全部失去
Clifford, don't. If something is lost, it needn't be all lost, need it?
如果没人想要我活，那我就没有理由活下去
There's no reason for me to live if nobody wants me to live.
刚才看见你在那里，我就想
Just seeing you there then...
如果我死了，你就可以解脱了，可能你也清楚这点
...I thought you'd be better off if I were dead. Perhaps you knew it.
我不想让你死
I don't want you to die...
可如果让我为你的生死承担责任，那就太残酷了
...but it is cruel to make me responsible for your living.
你自己想活，对不对？
you want to live, don't you?
亲爱的，对不起
Darling, I'm sorry.
我太无情了
I'm a real brute.
别哭，别因为…
Don't cry. Don't...
我的自私而哭，
...for my selfish sake.
我不值得你这样
I'm not worthy of you.
在这儿等着’，迈勒斯
Wait here, Mellors.
你来这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
迈勒斯，有什么事吗？
yes, Mellors, what is it?
我今天早上抓到两个偷猎者，还带着夹子和野兔
I caught a couple of poachers, sir, with snares and rabbits, this morning.
- 他们在哪儿  - 在外面，先生
- Where are they?  - Outside, sir.
我该怎么处置他们？
What should I do about them?
- 起诉  - 是，先生
- Prosecute.  - yes, sir.
有必要起诉吗？
Is it necessary to prosecute them?
偷猎野兔有必要吗？干这种事有必要吗？
Is it necessary to poach rabbits? Or anything else for that matter?
如果不起诉，满树林都是他们了
They'd be all over the wood if we didn't prosecute.
- 你们以前都是矿工吧？ - 是的，夫人
- you were colliers, weren't you?  - yes, milady.
你看，他们偷猎是因为饥饿…
you see, they're poaching because they're hungry...
夫人阁下说得对
Her ladyship is right.
我们不起诉了，放了他们
We won't prosecute. Let them go.
- 不过要先打一顿  - 克利夫德！
- After you've thrashed them.  - Clifford!
他要么打他们，要么结柬自己在这儿的工作
He'll thrash them, or he'll consider his employment here ended.
过去
Go on.
好！
Good!
谢谢，迈勒斯
Thank you, Mellors.
走吧
Come on, then.
- 你迟到了  - 我故意的
- you're late.  - I meant to be.
- 不是你想让我来的吗？ - 不是你自己想来才来的吗？
- Didn't you want me here?  - Is it only to be when you want?
偷猎者的事你觉得无所谓吗？
What happened to those poachers didn't bother you?
- 你好像无所谓呀  - 我能不服从命令吗？
- It didn't seem to bother you.  - Should I have disobeyed him?
即使这样，你也会打他们的
you would have beaten them anyway.
- 即便这样  - 你怎么了？夫人
- Even so.  - Even so, milady.
好啦，对不起
Okay, I'm sorry.
你现在够了
Good.
今天快多了，再做两个
Faster today. A couple more.
很好
That's good.
说实话，刚开始的时候
To be honest, when we started...
我没抱什么希望
...I thought it was hopeless.
可现在我觉得你能行
But now I think you can do it.
- 要是有了孩子怎么办？ - 我很愿意有孩子
- What happens if you have a child?  - I should like to have a child.
那克利夫德先生呢？
What about Sir Clifford?
克利夫德说过这事
Clifford talked about it.
- 他想要子嗣  - 什么？
- He wants a son and heir.  - What?
他知道我？
He knows about me?
不
No.
如果有了孩子，你会告诉他吗？
If you have a child, you'll tell him?
如果他怀疑你，我就不得不离开
If he ever suspects about you, I'd have to go away.
为什么？
What for?
离开你我活不下去
I couldn't live without you...
可如果他知道了你，我就无法和他生活下去
...but I couldn't live with him if he knew about you.
如果你走了，再也见不到我了，你会焦虑不安吗？
Wouldn't fret if you went away and never saw me again?
是的，我会在意，会焦虑不安
yes, I'd mind. I'd fret.
- 你会在意吗？ - 是的，我会
- Should you mind?  - Aye, that I would.
我想让要你骗一次人，去我的小屋过一夜，就一次
I should like you to lie one night with me at my cottage, just for once.
我必须要走了
I must go now.
对不起，夫人
Sorry, milady.
- 克利夫德先生呢？  - 在书房
- Where's Sir Clifford?  - In the library.
- 也许他没听见  - 我去告诉他
- Perhaps he didn't hear.  - I'll tell him.
夫人
Milady.
- 你不想吃晚餐吗？ - 想，我饿极了
- Aren't you coming in to dinner?  - yes, I'm starving.
我只是想把这些计划做完
I just want to finish with these plans.
什么计划？煤矿的？
What is it, the mine?
我无法开创一个朝代，无法像雷诺阿那样画画
I can't father a dynasty. I can't paint like Renoir.
但我可以做企业，康妮
It has to be business, Con.
查泰莱家族的姓氏一定要永远流传
Immortality must be the name Chatterley.
咱们就从煤矿开始
We start with the mine.
你在听我说话吗？
Are you listening to me?
咱们必须先在收入和资本方面做出牺牲
We'll have to make sacrifices in income and capital...
因为我们要进行现代化改造
...because we must modernise it.
晚安，克利夫德
Good night, Clifford.
晚安，康妮，睡个好觉
Good night, Con. Sleep well.
我真怕你今天不来了，
I was scared you wouldn't come today.
你为什么要找我这样一个下等人？
What do you come to a fellow like me for?
因为你可以想要就要，不想要就不要吗？
Because you can take it or leave it as you please?
我见过你一次，当时你在洗澡
I saw you once, washing.
- 我觉得你很美  - 我？
- I thought you were beautiful.  - Me?
你的身体很美，我想要你
your body was beautiful. I wanted you.
我的身体，很美？
My body, beautiful?
是你觉得吧？跟那些上层美少年比吗？
To you? As knows all the tiptop young fellas?
- 我说的不是漂亮  - 心灵美才是真美
- I don't mean handsome.  - Handsome is as handsome does.
你对我并不认真，对吧？
you don't take me serious, do you?
我在你面前是什么人？你们的人会怎么说？
What am I to you? What do your sort say?
说我是“鸭”？
A fucker?
不，是情人
No, lover.
你是我的情人
you are my lover.
你就是没结婚，也不会嫁给我
you wouldn't marry me if you was free.
你也不想让我嫁给你
you wouldn't want me to.
如果你不是高高在上的话，我会的
If you weren't above me, I should.
可你高高在上，看不起我
But you're above. you look down on me.
不，我非常感谢你
No, I'm grateful to you.
我也是
And me, I am too.
和你在一起超爽，可我说的不是这个
This is extra, but I don't mean this.
等你的时候
When I wait...
我望着空地那头，你没有来，我对自己说
...I look across the grounds and you don't come, I say:
“老兄，她今天不想要你
"She wants none of you today, lad.
还是拿着猎枪回去吧”
you best hang up your gun and go home."
- 你根本不拿我当回事  - 不对
- you think nothing of me.  - I do.
根本不在乎我
Not me.
你喜欢的只是这事
It's this you enjoy.
就是这样
And that's all.
不，你错了
No, you're wrong.
我真的爱你
I do love you.
我要去你的小屋和你一起睡，我一定要去
And I want to sleep with you in your cottage, and I will.
什么时候
When?
我想听你对我说，我的身体很美
I want you to tell me my body is beautiful.
我想做你的妻子，可我不能离开克利夫德
I would be your wife, but I can't leave Clifford.
他明白我需要有人
He understands I need somebody. you.
你难道不明白我需要他吗？
Don't you understand I need him?
如果他知道那个人是我，他会怎么说？
What would he say if he knew it were me?
不知道，我永远不会告诉他
I don't know. I'll never tell him.
你永远不会告诉他，因为你知道那样就会马上失去他
you'd never tell him, because you know you'd lose him right enough.
这和你我的阶级毫无关系
It's nothing to do with class.
有关系，有着数不清的关系
It's got everything to do with it. Everything.
那我们还是说再见吧
Then we'd better say goodbye.
你给我的远远超过我给你的
you've given me more than I've ever given you.
你肯定非常恨我
you must really hate me.
我以后再也不来了
I mustn't come here anymore.
等等，我不想让你走
Wait, I don't want you to go.
说点什么吧，让我一直想着，直到下次你再来
Say something that will keep until you come back here.
要我我说什么？
What shall I say?
说你永远不会断绝我们之间的关系
Say you'll never break it off between us.
我永远不会
I never will.
咱们去让这话合法
Then let's make it legal.
你愿不愿意把钉子永远钉进这棵树？
Will you drive your nail into this tree for good and all?
是的，我愿意
Yes, I am willing to
- 你什么时候和我一起过夜？ - 很快
- When will you stay the night with me?  - Soon.
- 你在这儿干什么？ - 我一直在看落日
- What are you doing?  - I've been watching the sunset.
可以了
That's all right.
你今天要却哪儿？
Where are you going today?
去林子里，看看小鸡孵出来没有
I'm going to the woods, see if the chicks have hatched.
能帮我把门打开吗？’
Can you open the gate for me?
谢谢
Thank you.
干嘛带他来？我一直以为在这林子里你是我的老婆
Why have you brought him? I thought you're to be my wife in the woods.
到这儿来是他的主意
It was his idea to come here.
他知道了？
Well, he knows?
- 不会的  - 他肯定起疑心了
- He can't.  - He must be suspicious.
康妮！
Connie!
你最好早点去我的小屋，以防万一
you'd better come to the cottage soon, just in case.
- 今天夜里  - 好，今天夜里
- Tonight.  - Aye, tonight.
- 康妮，你到底去哪儿了？ - 我来了
- Connie, where the devil are you?  - I'm coming.
好了
It's all right.
我还以为我会陷进去呢
I thought I was going to sink in, that's all.
使劲，推，推呀！
Come on. Push, push!
不行，咱们陷住了
It's no good. We're stuck.
迈勒斯！
Mellors!
迈勒斯，我是不是让什么东西绊住了？
Mellors. am I caught up somewhere?
是这样，先生
I should say you are, sir.
- 要我帮你推出去吗？ - 不用，让发动机来吧
- Shall I give you a push?  - No, let the motor do it.
我再试一下
I'll try again.
好吧，你来推吧
yes, you can push.
使劲，推呀！
Come on, man, push!
推呀！
Push!
推呀，迈勒斯！
Push, Mellors!
使劲！推呀！
Come on! Push.
快点，使劲推呀！
Come on. Put your back into it, man.
- 你是不是拉着闸呢，先生？ - 当然没有
- Have you got the brake on, sir?  - No, of course not.
等一下
Wait a minute.
齿轮坏了
The gears have gone.
你得把我推回去了
you'll have to push me in neutral.
帮他一把，康妮
Well, give him a hand, Connie.
处处让人同情真是太不好意思了
It is a shame to be at the mercy of anyone.
伯尔顿太太，请去叫一下纽曼
Mrs. Bolton, can you send for Newman?
不用麻烦他了，迈勒斯可依抱我
Don't bother him. Mellors can carry me.
- 对不起，迈勒斯？  - 是的，先生
- Can't you, Mellors?  - yes, sir.
康妮，把我的轮椅清洗干净，好吗？
Connie, tidy my chair away, will you?
我并不是很重吧，迈勒斯？
Not too heavy am I, Mellors?
别碰！
Don't touch those!
非常感谢，，迈勒斯
Thanks awfully, Mellors.
谢谢，先生
Thank you, sir.
- 出去散步很好吧？  - 是的，非常感谢
- Did you enjoy your walk?  - yes, thank you very much.
他真是个好人，你说是不是？
He's really quite a good sort, don't you think?
伯尔顿太太，请让菲尔德准备帮我洗澡
Mrs. B, ask Field to run me a bath, will you?
他觉得自己微不足道，像美国人说的，值不了几粒豆子
He thinks he's the whole hill of beans, as the Americans say.
他那种人
People like him...
即使伯尔顿太太那么好的人
...even Mrs. Bolton, nice as she is...
对我们也没有真正的尊敬
...they've no real respect for us.
也许只尊敬我们所拥有的，而不是我们的人
For what we've got, perhaps, not what we are.
他们应该尊敬吗？我们尊敬他们的人吗？
Ought they to? Do we respect them for what they are?
除了为我们干活，他们还有什么？
What are they, apart from what they do for us?
你能呼唤他们的道德灵魂吗？
Would you raise a shout about his soul?
只不过是行尸走肉
He's just so much live human meat.
谢谢，伯尔顿太太
Thank you, Mrs. B.
你真的来了
So you've come, then?
你都看见了
Obviously.
没事吧？你真的想来吧？
Is it all right? you wanted to come?
当然了，否则我不会来的
Of course. Otherwise I wouldn't.
我很高兴
I'm glad you did.
我真是太高兴了
I'm so glad you did.
这里很温馨舒适
It's cosy in here.
- 好漂亮  - 哦，你说花呀
- They're pretty.  - The flowers.
- 她就是这样的  - 谁？
- So that's what she looks like.  - Who?
- 这是你妻子，对吧？ - 你怎么知道？
- It is your wife, isn't it?  - How do you know?
我知道你的不少事
I know a lot about you.
咱们来这儿可不是聊她的
Well, we didn't come here to talk about her.
当然不是，可我不能不想到她
No, but I have to think about her.
不管怎么说，你肯定曾经爱过他
After all, you must have liked her once.
她跑了，她现在不是我的妻子，这事已经结束了
She ran off. She's not my wife now, so there's an end to it.
康妮？
Connie?
你疯了
you're crazy.
你就像是夜晚的一座雕像
you look a figure out here in the night.
- 我还漂亮吗？ - 漂亮，在月光下
- am I still beautiful?  - Aye, under the moon.
在这个世界上，你比月亮还漂亮
you're more of the moon than this world.
天空是真实的，树林是真实的，你也是真实的
The sky is real, the woods are real, and you are real.
- 在林子里，我是你的妻子  - 在哪里你都是我妻子
- I am your wife in the woods.  - Aye, my wife anywhere.
我以前从没有过妻子
I never had a wife before.
从来不知道女人什么样
I never knew what a woman was like before.
天亮了
It's day.
咱们还有时间
We have time.
我现在知道了和人睡在一起是怎么回事
Now I know what it's like to sleep with someone.
- 什么？ - 没什么？
- What?  - Nothing.
我得走了
I should go now.
和我在一起吧
Stay with me.
真冷
It's cold.
- 怎么了？ - 我算什么人？
- What's wrong?  - What sort of man am I?
让一个不能动的人呼来唤去背地里操他的老婆
Running around at the call of a paralysed man and fucking his wife.
对你来说，我算什么人？
What sort of a mate am I for you?
除了做爱，你还尊敬我什么？
How can you respect me except for fucking?
- 而做爱，人人都会  - 听着，没有人会那样做
- And almost anyone would do for that.  - Here, no other man would do for that.
我不能进入你的圈子，你也不能进入我的
I can't go among your people, you can't come to mine.
- 所有这些社会上的东西重要吗？ - 是的，重要
- Does all that social stuff matter?  - Aye, it matters.
有多重要？
How much?
这么重要？
This much?
你得走了
you must go.
咱们以后还要这样
We'll have another time like this.
克利夫德？
Clifford?
克利夫德
Clifford.
你可以告诉我这都不是真的
you could tell me it's all untrue.
“去吧，康妮，如果愿意，就去找个男人，只是不要离开我”
"Go ahead, Connie. Take a man if you wish, only never leave me."
- 找个男人，康妮，而不是可恶的…  - 农民？奴隶？
- A man, Connie, not a damn...  - Peasant? Slave?
你要是怀孕了怎么办，夫人？好好想想
What if you got pregnant, milady? Think of that.
想想我
Think of me.
想想将来
Think of the future.
我想过会是什么人，可那该死的奥利弗·迈勒斯…
I thought of who it might be, but that damned Oliver Mellors....
奥利弗，他的名字？
Oliver, is it?
你连他的名字都没问过
you never even asked his name.
我已经把你的事情都安排好了，给你姐姐发了电报
I've made all the arrangements. I sent a telegram to your sister...
告诉她，你坐十点半的火车去伦敦
...you'll be on the 10:30 train to London...
三点半轮船从维多利亚出发
...and the 3:30 boat train on from Victoria.
我们都需要时间考虑一下
We both need time to think.
- 一路顺风，夫人  - 谢谢，菲尔德
- Have a good journey, milady.  - Thank you, Field.
能不能帮我做件事？
Could you do something for me?
请告诉迈勒斯一声
Please tell Mellors.
亲爱的，我能离开我丈夫，你也能离开你丈夫
Darling, if I left my husband, you can leave yours.
你已经和那个看守猎场的人走出了第一步
you've made the first move with this gamekeeper chap.
为什么第二步、第羞步、第四步就那么困难呢？
Why are the second, third and fourth moves so difficult?
对你来说很容易，对我来说没那么容易
It's not as easy for me as it is for you.
我不喜欢看到你这个样子，我会让你重新微笑
I don't like seeing you like this. I'll make you smile again.
请在这儿等我一会儿，好吗？
Can you wait for me here, please?
康妮，看看我给你找来了什么？
Connie, look what I've found for you.
你想要哪个？
Which one do you want?
哪个都不想要，你都留着吧，一会儿见
Not for me. Have them both. I'll see you later.
听见我说话了吗？你怎么一言不发地总站在这里？
Are you listening? How can you stand it here all the time?
我喜欢在这儿，这让我左右为难的窘境显得更为英勇
I quite enjoy it here. It makes my dilemma seem even more heroic.
左右为难？这儿有你一封信
Dilemma? This letter's arrived for you.
希望是好消息
I hope that it's good news.
咱们一会儿见
I'll see you in a minute.
康妮，亲爱的，走啊
Connie, dear, come on.
你不想游泳吗？
Don't you want to go swimming?
说实话，康妮，你太让人扫兴了
Honestly, Connie, you're such a bore.
克利夫德安排你远走国外
Clifford arranges it by sending you into exile...
可大家都做的事，你偏不做
...and all you do is the exact opposite of what everyone else wants to do.
怀孕的女人是可以胡思乱想的
Pregnant women are allowed their whims.
- 你不可能怀孕  - 我怀孕了，刚看过医生
- you can't be pregnant.  - I am. I've seen a doctor.
这太可怕了
Absolutely awful.
可我觉得这是最好的喜事
It's the best thing that ever happened to me.
别傻了
Don't be silly.
- 我们该拿你和那个怎么办？  - 送我回英国
- What will we do with you and it?  - Get me back to England.
- 克利夫德  - 等一下
- Clifford?  - Wait.
- 欢迎回家，夫人  - 你好
- Welcome back, milady.  - Hello.
这是不是奇迹？都是伯尔顿太太的功劳
Isn't it simply wonderful? And all Mrs. B's doing.
我的鼓励，克利夫德先生，主要是你的意志力
My encouragement, perhaps, Sir Clifford, your will-power.
当心！没事吧？
Be careful! Are you all right?
真是费了大劲了，不过确实值得
It's the devil of an effort but really worth it.
- 最袁的成就是下到了矿井里  - 什么？
- Going down the mine was the triumph.  - What?
我在信上都写了，你没收到我的信吗？
I wrote you about it. Didn't you get my letters?
我把所有事情都写信告诉你了
I wrote you about everything.
奥利弗？
Oliver?
夫人？哦，他已经不在这儿工作了
Milady? Oh, he don't work here no more.
有什么重要的事吗？
Was it anything important?
没有，谢谢，对不起打扰你了
No, thank you. I'm sorry to have troubled you.
- 迈勒斯出什么事了？ - 他走了，克利夫德先生解雇了他
- What's happened to Mellors?  - He's gone. Sir Clifford dismissed him.
明白了
I see.
克利夫德，你最好把一切都告诉我
you'd better tell me everything.
- 告诉什么？  - 迈勒斯的事
- About what?  - Mellors.
迈勒斯？
Mellors?
我给你的信上都写了
I wrote you about it. It was in my letters.
你的信我没看，快告诉我
I didn't read your letters. Tell me.
我还以为你因为那个原因不回信呢
I thought you didn't answer them, because of that.
听说你要回来，我还以为你原谅了我
When I heard you were coming back, I thought you'd forgiven me.
因为什么原因？
Because of what?
他确实不想留在这儿
He didn't want to stay.
你送走了我，解雇了他，我真不敢相信
you sent me away, and you dismissed him. I can't believe it.
我不想让你太痴迷他
I didn't want you to become too fond of him.
我知道我们达成过一致，你可以有情人
I know we agreed about you having a lover...
但我这样做是因为你，是为了减轻你的痛苦
...but I did it because of you, to save you pain.
毕竟我们讨论过子嗣的事
After all, we did talk about a son and heir...
如果你见他的次数太多
...and if you'd saw too much of him...
谁知道顶我姓氏的会是什么杂种
...who knows what bastards I'd give my name.
- 你的姓氏  - 康妮，你清楚我的立场
- your name.  - Con, surely you understand my position.
克利夫德，我怀孕了
Clifford, I'm pregnant.
他是孩子的父亲，你的姓氏完了
He's the father, and your name be damned.
告诉你吧，在煤矿外面干活越来越难了
I tell you, love, work outside the mine is getting hard to come by.
- 你来这儿干什么？ - 我刚回来
- What are you doing here?  - I just got back.
- 是吗？你想干什么？ - 拜托…
- Did you, now? What do you want?  - Please...
听着，这一切已经不可能了，事情已经结束了
Look, it can't be the way it was, so there's an end to it.
你不想再要我了吗？
But don't you want me anymore?
我想和你在一起
I want to be with you.
我不想在我的一生中没有你
I don't want to miss you all my life.
如果你真恨我，为什么还要为查泰菜家干苦力？
If you hate me, how can you still slave for the Chatterleys?
- 听说过加拿大吗？ - 什么？
- Have you heard of Canada?  - What?
加拿大，每周十四镑工钱，我在为自己挣路费
Canada, 14 pounds a week. I'm working to earn my fare.
- 听我说，我都计划好了  - 不
- Listen to me, I've got it all planned...  - No.
你怎么会喜欢我这种人？
How can you like the likes of me?
- 奥利弗，我怀孕了  - 他妈的
- Oliver, I'm pregnant.  - Damn you.
你得到了你想要的，克利夫德先生得到了孩子
you got what you want, and Sir Clifford gets a child.
不，孩子会姓我娘家姓，或是你的姓
No, it will have my maiden name or your name.
不会再有姓查泰菜的人了，克利夫德是最后一个
There will be no other Chatterley. Clifford is the last.
不管你和不和我在一起，我都会离开他
I'll leave him, whether you come or not.
咱们去哪儿？咱们干什么？我能干什么？
And where will we go? What will we do? What will I do?
你可以经营自己的农场
you could run your own farm.
- 怎么经营？ - 可以用我的收入
- How?  - We could use my income.
你看不到自己活得像个奴隶吗？
Can't you see you live like a slave?
- 我让自己自由了，你也可以  - 我不做吃软饭的男人
- I've made myself free. you can too.  - I'll not be a kept man.
我们的孩子，不属于哪个阶级，是你我最好部分的结合
And our child, no class. The best of you, the best of me.
你还记得吗？
Do you remember?
“我的夜晚就不会被懊悔吞噬”
"My nights will not be haunted by regrets."
- 你真的觉得我很美？ - 你就是很美
- So you really think I'm beautiful?  - you are.
- 还有多长时间？ - 七个月
- How long to go?  - Seven months.
咱们等着吧，等着吧
We'll see, we'll see.
康妮？
Connie?